Garret Gallant

Denver, Colorado | 303-523-0283 | gallanttechnological@gmail.com LinkedIn | Github | Blog

Full-Stack Software Engineer

Experienced in Ruby on Rails and JavaScript based programming with a background in Software Engineering and Hardware Diagnostics/Repair. Possesses strong skills in communication and teamwork that help development teams drive what makes applications efficient, scalable, and user-friendly. From a very young age I've been inspired to innovate and inspire positive change in the quality of everyday life using technology as my medium; I hope to do so with your company as well!

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Ruby | Rails | React | JavaScript | TypeScript | Java | HTML | CSS | Active Storage | AWS S3 | Heroku | SCRUM/AGILE Development Tailwind UI | Semantic UI | PostgreSQL | SQLite

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Bandmate.com - Github | Demo

Bandmate was designed to allow musicians to connect and form bands more easily over the internet.

- Utilized JSON Web Tokens and Rails BCrypt to store encrypted user login information.
- Utilized Rails Active Storage to allow users to upload and store audio files to remote database.
- Designed frontend visuals and parsed JSON return data from custom backend for user-friendly frontend.
- Built Rails actions to formulate and serialize JSON data for optimized returns that contains all necessary information for each frontend component view.

Haku Mele - Github | Demo

Haku Mele was created as a catalog of songs that users can visit for new music.

- Designed a component based frontend to create an intuitive and visually appealing user experience.
- Built and seeded JSON data for the frontend to parse and display.
- Created a random generation algorithm and applied it synchronously to the frontend for new music.
- Added filter's for ease of use on the browser page, so users can more effectively sort by their needs.

StackOverflat - Github | Demo (coming soon)

Stackoverflat was made to emulate a discussion forum where users can post about any topic to chat about.

- Created a relational database to contain users, posts, and comments.
- Utilized JSON Web Tokens and Rails BCrypt to store encrypted user login information.
- Built nested components for the profile page to dynamically render components within a single page route.
- Dynamically rendered JSON data based on all user-made categories on the site.

EXPERIENCE

King Systems LLC

Golden, CO

A/V System Service & Implementation

08/2021 - 07/2022

- Installed and serviced complex, secure network enabled A/V systems for large-scale commercial integrations
- Inspired teamwork and positivity to implement workflow changes that maintain optimal efficiency within my team.

UBreakIFixLittleton, COTeam Manager08/2018 - 08/2021

- Facilitated hardware/software diagnostics and repairs on a wide range of electronic devices.
- Managed staff and inventory alongside task delegation to maintain high efficiency and turnaround rates.
- Managed partner relationships w/ Samsung, Apple, and Google.

EDUCATION

Flatiron School

Denver, CO

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program

07/2022 - 10/2022

MSU Denver

Partially Complete, Bachelors in Computer Science

Denver, CO 03/2018-08/2020